An epic quest. A magical guitar pick. A chance to put the D in Destiny.
Tenacious D in The Pick of Destiny is a comedy, music,
fantasy film directed by Liam Lynch.
In Venice Beach, naive Midwesterner JB bonds with local
slacker KG and they form the rock band Tenacious D.
Setting out to become the world's greatest band is no easy feat, so they set
out to steal what could be the answer to their prayers...
a magical guitar pick housed in a rock-and-roll museum some 300 miles away.
JB, played by Jack Black.
KG, played by Kyle Gass.
Lee, played by JR Reed.
Dio, played by Ronnie James Dio.
Open Mic Host, played by Paul F. Tompkins.
Lil' JB, played by Troy Gentile.
Tenacious D in The Pick of Destiny is a 2006 American musical
fantasy comedy film about comedy rock duo Tenacious D.
Written, produced by and starring Tenacious D members Jack Black and Kyle Gass, it
is directed and co-written by musician and puppeteer Liam Lynch.
Despite being about an actual band, the film is a fictitious story about the band's origins, and their
journey to find a magical pick belonging to Satan that allows its users to become rock legends.
The film was released on November 22, 2006, and was a box office bomb.
The soundtrack, The Pick of Destiny, was also released in
2006 as the band's second studio album.
Despite the mixed box office reception of the film at release,
it has since been considered a cult classic.
The film explores themes of rock 'n' roll, guitar,
rock star, music competition, satan.
The tone is lighthearted.